[
    {
        "question": "What island does the The Statue of Liberty stand on?",
        "answer": "Liberty Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What town`s name means `House of Bread` in Hebrew?",
        "answer": "Bethlehem"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Atomium is a famous tourist attraction in which city?",
        "answer": "Brussels"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European city would you find the `Atomium` landmark?",
        "answer": "Brussels"
    },
    {
        "question": "What waterway divides Turkey between Europe and Asia?",
        "answer": "Bosphorus Strait"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Valley of the Moon?",
        "answer": "Jordan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s largest landlocked country?",
        "answer": "Kazakhstan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the highest percentage of federal land?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What three countries does Borneo belong to?",
        "answer": "Indonesia, Malaysia, and Brunei"
    },
    {
        "question": "Madagascar is located off the coast of what mainland country?",
        "answer": "Mozambique"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state flower of Arizona?",
        "answer": "Saguaro cactus blossom -- Pronounced sa-WAH-ro, it grows only in a specific area of the Sonoran Desert, and is found in no other U.S. state outside of Arizona."
    },
    {
        "question": "What non-flower is the state flower of Maine?",
        "answer": "Pine cone -- Maine even sent pine cones as its representation in the National Garland of Flowers arrangement the U.S. prepared for the 1893 World`s Fair."
    },
    {
        "question": "What common plant of the American West is the state flower of Nevada?",
        "answer": "Sagebrush -- It is common in the southwest, but it is not a true desert shrub. It has been used by Native Americans to make teas with healing properties."
    },
    {
        "question": "The official bud of five states, what is the most common state flower?",
        "answer": "Rose -- North Dakota, Georgia, Iowa, New York and Oklahoma. Washington, D.C. claims American Beauty Rose as its official flower. The rose is also America`s national flower."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. Interstate highway is the longest?",
        "answer": "I-90"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Valentine`s Day called in Brazil?",
        "answer": "Dia dos Namorados"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest city in South America?",
        "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What `colorful` Sea lies between northeast China and the Korean peninsula?",
        "answer": "Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country is the Nobel Peace Prize awarded?",
        "answer": "Norway"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 608?",
        "answer": "Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest lake by area in the British Isles?",
        "answer": "Lough Neagh"
    },
    {
        "question": "What`s the capital of Comoros?",
        "answer": "Moroni"
    },
    {
        "question": "India became an independent country in what year?",
        "answer": "1947"
    },
    {
        "question": "Christmas Island is a territory belonging to which country?",
        "answer": "Australia "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state, now the second largest state, was once an independent republic?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital city of the U.S. Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Charlotte Amalie"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country dominates the Jutland Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Italian region is the source of Marsala wine?",
        "answer": "Sicily"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was Breakneck Ridge in World War II?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the biggest island in Canada?",
        "answer": "Baffin Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest public art museum in the United States?",
        "answer": "Wadsworth Atheneum"
    },
    {
        "question": "What structure links Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario?",
        "answer": "Ambassador Bridge"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two notable leaders attended the Casablanca Conference?",
        "answer": "Roosevelt and Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which capital name means `City of Joy?`",
        "answer": "Bucharest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Excluding Mexico, which Central American capital cities share their names with their country?",
        "answer": "El Salvador, Guatemala and Panama"
    },
    {
        "question": "What modern country includes the ancient region of Mesopotamia?",
        "answer": "Iraq"
    },
    {
        "question": "What color is the cross on the flag of Finland?",
        "answer": "Blue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is located across the Columbia River from the city of Vancouver?",
        "answer": "Portland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount hotham is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Buenos Aires is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Knesset?",
        "answer": "Israel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Bundestag?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Duma?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The States-General?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Althing?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fortress known as the Mir Castle Complex is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Belarus -- It is quite a beautiful UNESCO World Heritage Site."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was the first to have its own phone number?",
        "answer": "Sweden -- The official phone number (+46 771 793 336), is part of a marketing campaign from the Swedish Tourist Association."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mason-Dixon Line also called the Mason and Dixon Line forms part of the borders for which U.S. states?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware and West Virginia (Virginia until 1863)"
    }
]